<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AWS on Data By Dan</title>
    <link>https://danbernstein.netlify.app/tags/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AWS on Data By Dan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;#169; 2020 Softorage. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://danbernstein.netlify.app/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Commons Mistakes When Using the AWS Cloud Development Kit</title>
      <link>https://danbernstein.netlify.app/post/2020-10-16-commons-errors-using-the-aws-cloud-development-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danbernstein.netlify.app/post/2020-10-16-commons-errors-using-the-aws-cloud-development-kit/</guid>
      <description>The AWS Cloud Development Kit (CDK) is a set of tools that make it easy to write code to specify cloud infrastructure and deploy it using common scripting languages, like Python or Javascript. Previously, you had to use YAML or XML templates to deploy AWS cloud infrastructure using the CloudFormation service. The CDK is a wrapper around these templates that makes Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) more accessible and allows you to take advantage of complex operations that you cannot accomplish in template files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copying Millions of Files Between S3 Buckets Without Managing Servers</title>
      <link>https://danbernstein.netlify.app/post/2020-10-16-copying-millions-of-files-between-s3-buckets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danbernstein.netlify.app/post/2020-10-16-copying-millions-of-files-between-s3-buckets/</guid>
      <description>Issue: I need to copy thousands or millions of files between S3 buckets. This might be because you regularly move data between a test and a production environments or your data architecture has changed and the new bucket names make more sense. Whether you are doing it once or regularly, there are multiple options for moving a large number of files between buckets, and the choice might come down to your familiarity with different AWS computing services, such as Lambda, EC2, and EMR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Way to Understand AWS Services</title>
      <link>https://danbernstein.netlify.app/post/2020-09-13-a-simple-way-to-understand-aws-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danbernstein.netlify.app/post/2020-09-13-a-simple-way-to-understand-aws-services/</guid>
      <description>A quick glance at the list of services available on AWS can be overwhelming. As of September 2020, there are over 160 AWS services, some of which have informative names, such as simple storage service (S3), and others which are incredibly obtuse, like Neptune and Greengrass. The number and variety of services has even inspired catchy songs. Looking at the list, you might start to think, “do I need to use all of those to build my application?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
