<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>javascript on Data By Dan</title>
    <link>https://danbernstein.netlify.app/tags/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in javascript on Data By Dan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;#169; 2020 Softorage. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://danbernstein.netlify.app/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Developing a Chrome Extension To Parse Recipes</title>
      <link>https://danbernstein.netlify.app/post/recipe-scraper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danbernstein.netlify.app/post/recipe-scraper/</guid>
      <description>I love cooking, and I am heavily dependent on a couple of websites for new recipe ideas. Oftentimes, these websites contain multiple advertisements to drive revenue or the recipe contains a lot of background information that is not immediately relevant to the recipe, such as the history of the dish or how the chef developed the recipe.
Problem: I love cooking but I hate all of this irrelevant content on recipe websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping and Visualizing My Rideshare and Bicycling Activity</title>
      <link>https://danbernstein.netlify.app/post/2019-05-12/visualizing-personal-transportation-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danbernstein.netlify.app/post/2019-05-12/visualizing-personal-transportation-use/</guid>
      <description>Summary: This small project started out with two goals: web scraping and visualizing movement data. As the project developed, I found that the web scraping took most of the time, and the visualization was best left to well-developed javascript frameworks, rather than developing it from scratch.
Check out the final visualization.
Webscraping Note: It is extremely important to read and understand the website user agreement for any website from which you might want to scrape data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
